Guide to the N. Scott Momaday Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual materials, 1965-2009
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Songs of the Southwest", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "From the Eagle's Bed, Wilford Numkena", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "From the Eagle's Bed, Wilford Numkena", undated (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Crow Celebration" 1972 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Crow Celebration" 1972 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "My Beautiful Land and other Navajo Songs, Danny Whitefeather Begay, Cindy Yazzie & Roger McCabe" 1971 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "My Beautiful Land and other Navajo Songs, Danny Whitefeather Begay, Cindy Yazzie & Roger McCabe" 1971, 1972 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "My Beautiful Land and other Navajo Songs, Danny Whitefeather Begay, Cindy Yazzie & Roger McCabe" 1971 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "My Beautiful Land and other Navajo Songs, Danny Whitefeather Begay, Cindy Yazzie & Roger McCabe" 1971 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "My Beautiful Land and other Navajo Songs, Danny Whitefeather Begay, Cindy Yazzie & Roger McCabe" 1971 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Soundchief's Enterprise Authentic Indian Recordings: Kiowa Flag and Honor Ceremony Songs" 1966 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Soundchief's Enterprise Authentic Indian Recordings: Kiowa Tribal Tia-Piah Society Songs" 1966 (Box 45 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Kiowa Gourd Dance Vol. 1" 1975 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Kiowa Church Songs" 1972 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Music of the Pueblos Apache and Navaho" 1961 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Records: Section IR 320 Southern Cheyenne Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Peyote Healing Chants of the Native American Church" 1972 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Traditional Navajo Songs" 1969 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Squaw Dance Songs" 1970 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Sway Songs" 1968 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Viva California" 1969 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Taos Round Dance Part 2" 1970 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Songs of the Redman: authentic Indian Recordings of Southern and Northern Plains Tribes", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Authentic Music of the American Indian" three record set., undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Music of the American Indian: Plains: Comanche, Cheyenne, Kiowa, Caddo, Wichita, Pawnee", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Music of the American Indian: Apache", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Music of the American Indian: Navaho", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Gift Songs & Round Dance" 1971 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Gift Songs & Round Dance" 1971 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Social Songs sung by Robert E. Lee" 1971 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Social Songs sung by Robert E. Lee" 1971 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Navajo Social Songs sung by Robert E. Lee" 1971 (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "American Indian Soundchief: Northern Cheyenne War Dance Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "American Indian Soundchief: Northern Cheyenne War Dance Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "American Indian Soundchief: Kiowa Peyote Ritual Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "American Indian Soundchief: Kiowa Peyote Ritual Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "American Indian Soundchief: Kiowa Black Leg Warriors Society Ceremonial Dance", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 12" Vinyl Record 33 rpm LP "Indian Records: Crow Grass Dance Songs (War Dance)", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Caddo Tribal Bell Dance (Social Dance)", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Modern Squaw Dance: Navajo", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Kiowa 425: When my Heart is Downcast the Lord Lifted Me Up", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Kiowa 425: When my Heart is Downcast the Lord Lifted Me Up", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Little Water (Old Time Navajo Skip Dance)", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Crow Slow War Dance", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Cheyenne Tribal Honor Songs", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Redman's Friendship Dance: Kiowa Hay-Yeah-Yoh", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "A Women Dance: Kiowa Plains Tribes Harvest Dance", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Kiowa Ohoma Society Dances", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - 10" Vinyl Record "Kiowa Tribal War Dances", undated (Box 46 (Record Album Storage))
  - "Momaday Art (CANON)", undated (Box 80)
    CD-R: One disc of artwork by N. Scott Momaday (CANON)
  - "Robert H. Henry", 2008 (Box 106)
    CD: "The Investiture of the Honorable Robert H. Henry as Chief Judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit" (University of Oklahoma, January 25 2008)
  - "Writing Out Loud", undated (Box 106)
    CD: "Writing Out Loud" w/ N. Scott Momaday and Teresa Miller undated
  - "Billy", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Billy" (based on an excerpt from "The Ancient Child" by N. Scott Momaday)
  - "Leap Partnership", 1999 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Leap Partnership" 2:15 min.
  - "Voices from Texas", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Voices from Texas" (dir. Ray Santisteban, Austin TX) 1 hr.
  - "Elma", 2004 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Elma": Rough Cut 4-1-04 27:00 min.
  - "Oklahoma", 1995 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Oklahoma: A remarkable film about a world-class State" (Oklahoma Heritage Assoc., 1995) 57:00 min.
  - "N. Scott Momaday at Border Book Festival", 2003 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "N. Scott Momaday at Border Book Festival" April 5, 2003 (dir. Ray Santisteban, Austin TX)
  - "Wheelwright Museum", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Wheelwright Museum of the American Indian"
  - "Remembered Earth" (1), 2002 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Remembered Earth": Location footage 2002 8:18 min.
  - "Fritz Scholder", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Fritz Scholder: Painting the Paradox"
  - "In the White Man's Image", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "In the White Man's Image"
  - "Science, Shaman and Sage", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Science, Shaman and Sage": Demo Tape (Patrick Holian, Las Cruces NM) 2:30 min.
  - "Ceremonial", 1999-2000 (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Ceremonial: Arte Contemporanea Degli Indiana D'America" (w/ letter)
  - "Amato", undated (Box 87)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Amato: A Love Affair with Opera" (dir. Stephen Ives" 63:24 min.
  - "Dancing with Photons", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Dancing with Photons" (Chain Reaction Prod., Santa Fe NM) 26:46 min.
  - "The Buffalo War", 2000 (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "The Buffalo War": (dir. Matthew Testa, 2000) 56:40 min.
  - "Keep It Alive", 1999 (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Keep It Alive: The AIHEC Cultural Learning Center Project" (Murray Bruce Prod., July 14, 1999)
  - "The White Man's Way", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "The White Man's Way"
  - "Somogi", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Somogi" by Jerry Olson 29:05 min.
  - "An American Portrait", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "An American Portrait: Oklahoma Summer Arts Institute" 29:00 min.
  - "Future Perfect", 1999 (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Future Perfect: Conversations for the New Millennium" 1/6/99 (two copies) 56:45 min.
  - "Reflections of a Bone Hunter", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Reflections of a Bone Hunter: The Life and Work of Loren Eiseley" (KUON, Lincoln NB) 57:41 min.
  - "Remembered Earth" (2), [2002] (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Remembered Earth: New Mexico's High Desert" (prod. John Grabowska) (two copies) 27:40 min.
  - "Vanishing Link", undated (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Vanishing Link" (promo): (prod. Donna M. Rowell, 2002) 4:25 min.
  - "Green Gold", 1992 (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Green Gold: From the Maya to the Moon" (NMSU and Purdue U., 1992)
  - "Colores", 1996 (Box 88)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Colores: America's Changing West" (KNME, Albuquerque NM, 1996)
  - "19 Masterpieces", 2001 (Box 89)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "19 Masterpieces of the Oral and Intangible Heritage of Humanity" (First Proclamation of Masterpieces, 18 May 2001, UNESCO, Paris)
  - "Heroes of the Cerro Grande", 2000 (Box 89)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Heroes of the Cerro Grande: Many Cultures, One People" (Code of the West Foundation, 2000) 85 min.
  - "Allan Houser", 1998 (Box 89)
    VHS VIDEO TAPE: "Allan Houser Haozous: The Lifetime Work of an American Master" (Allan Houser, Inc., Santa Fe NM) promo copy
  - "National Poetry Recitation Contest", 2005 (Box 89)
    CD: "National Poetry Recitation Contest" (NEA, 2005) (five copies w/ cover letter and promo)
  - "Operation Homecoming", 2004 (Box 89)
    CD: "Operation Homecoming: Writing the wartime experience" (NEA, 2004)
  - "Great American Voices", undated (Box 89)
    CD: "Great American Voices: Military Base Tour"
  - "Rudolfo Anaya", 2007 (Box 89)
    CD: "The Big Read: "Bless Me, Ultima" by Rudolfo Anaya: audio guide w/ booklet
  - "Willa Cather", 2006 (Box 89)
    CD: "The Big Read: Willa Cather's "My Antonia": audio guide w/ booklet
  - "John Steinbeck", 2006 (Box 89)
    CD: "The Big Read: John Steinbeck's "The Grapes of Wrath": audio guide w/ booklet
  - "Circle of Wonder", undated (Box 89)
    AUDIO CASSETTE: "Circle of Wonder: A Native American Christmas Story" by N. Scott Momaday (UofNM Press) (six copies)
  - "Directing the View", 2004 March 31 (Box 147)
    VHS video cassette, "Directing the View," The Venice Biennial, 2003 by M.J. Brocacci, 29 min., March 31, 2004
  - "Momaday Interview 3/11/03, House made of Dawn (film)", 2003 March 11 (Box 147)
    AUDIO CASSETTE: "Momaday Interview 3/11/03, House made of Dawn (film)"
  - "Rachmaninoff" (Box 147)
    AUDIO CASSETTE: "Rachmaninoff: Isle of the Dead; Vocalise; Rhapsody in Athenie of Paganini; Suite #1 for 2 pianos"
  - "Man Made of Words", undated (Box 147)
    "Man Made of Words, N. S. Momaday"
  - "Vanishing Link: My Spiritual Return to the Kiowa Way", 2004 (Box 147)
    DVD: "Vanishing Link: My Spiritual Return to the Kiowa Way" by Donna M. Rowell (2004)
  - "Before There Were Parks", 2009 (Box 147)
    DVD: "Before There Were Parks": Narrated by N. Scott Momaday (2009)
  - "The Indolent Boys" (radio play), undated (Box 147)
    CD: "The Indolent Boys" by N. Scott Momaday (radio version): Los Angeles: Autry National Center undated (two copies)
  - "A Celebration of Southwest Storytellers", undated (Box 147)
    CD: "A Celebration of Southwest Storytellers: Anaya, Hillerman & Momaday": Albuquerque: New Mexico Endowment for the Humanities (two copies)
  - "Songs of the Forest Nenets", 2002 (Box 147)
    CD: "Songs of the Forest Nenets: Music of the Finno-Urgic Peoples" (Estonian Literary Museum, 2002)
  - "When I Hear Thunder", undated (Box 147)
    VHS TAPE: "When I Hear Thunder": Denver: Denver Center Media undated: FINE CUT 108 min.
  - "Alaska & Bretagne", undated (Box 147)
    VHS TAPE: "Scott: Alaska & Bretagne" (8 min)
  - "War, Mother, Gourd Dance", 1976 (Box 147)
    CASSETTE TAPE: "War//Mother//Gourd Dance" (11-30-76)
  - "House Made of Dawn", 1999 (Box 147)
    CASSETTE TAPES: "House Made of Dawn" (unabridged) by N. Scott Momaday (Recorded Books, 1999): set of five audio cassettes in box
  - "An Interview with N. Scott Momaday", 2001 (Box 147)
    VHS TAPE: "An Interview with N. Scott Momaday" by Francoise Besson and Christiane Fioupou (23 min, 2001)